The whole point is that a business is
supposed to produce cash that eventually
comes out of the business.
>> Everyone has way more money than they
think, but just tied up in inventory and
cash and paying your people and whatever
else. Well, you really have to count the
cost before going all in on e-commerce.
In our business, is 60% of my sales
happen now, Q4, right? [laughter] So,
it's like I have to start working up my
inventory position because you can't
just double things overnight.
>> If you're in your 20s and early 30s, you
should be grinding hard so that when
you're in your 40s, you get to enjoy it
and then when you're in your 50s, you
enjoy it more and then when you're 60s,
you can just chill.
>> I plan on giving my kids no money or at
least telling them they're not going to
get any money.
Welcome to The Operators Podcast. My
name is Mike Beckham and I'll be with
you today along with Shawn and Jason.
We're going to be talking about money,
money, money. Like, how does cash flow
through your business? How do you
reinvest in your business? What do you
do with cash that comes out of your
business? How do you think about it?
It's kind of the point of the game that
we're playing, so we think it'll be
really helpful to everybody listening.
But before we get started, want to say a
special thank you to Sarah's, Rich
Panel, Postscript, Northbeam, Fulfill.
These are the sponsors that make the pod
possible. We are so thankful for their
support and we're ready to get into it.
Let's go.
>> [music]
>> Jones Road Beauty, Cody, this ad read is
just for you. I use Fulfill, Bruüns uses
Fulfill, Cuts uses Fulfill, Hexclad uses
Fulfill. Why did we all choose Fulfill?
Fulfill will help you move off in a
matter of weeks. There's no expensive
middleware, there's no third-party
developers, there's no consultants off
Upwork you got to hire. Fulfill will do
everything. You can be live in a couple
of weeks for order management, inventory
management, accounting, EDI, purchasing,
and manufacturing.
All those, that's the the full
soup-to-nuts
uh modules that they offer.
Pick one, choose one, do all of them,
whatever. Fulfill is here to make stuff
work for you. There's a reason why Cuts
left Nuts 'n Sweet. There's a reason why
Bruüns, the greatest e-com brand of the
past 5 years, was looking at all of them
and they chose Fulfill. Have you seen my
eight sleep scores? I'm getting 80s, 90s
every single night and that's cuz
Fulfill. I'm sleeping soundly because I
know Fulfill is working seamlessly
behind the scenes to deal with all of my
order volume. If I do 1,000 orders or
10,000 orders, Fulfill does not care. It
pipes these orders directly to my 3PL
and takes care of everybody. They are
the number one ERP for this podcast for
a reason. They're our number one
sponsor. I use them, Cuts uses them,
Hexclad uses them, Bruüns uses them,
everybody uses them. Mention The
Operators Podcast and you can use them,
too. Thank you so much for being the
number one sponsor. Thank you, listener,
for listening and I'll talk to you
later. Goodbye.
What I was thinking we talk about today
is just how we manage cash in the
business and start all the way back kind
of at the beginning with how we've done
it across uh the years with our
companies because it's actually kind of
like the whole point, right? Is that a
business is supposed to produce cash
that eventually comes out of the
business. And I wanted to talk really
tactically, practically about how did
that look for us? So, what I was
thinking we could do is like start by
going all the way back to like origin
story of the early days of Ridge,
Hexclad, Simple Modern.
And how long did you live in that era of
100% of the cash that the business
generates? And so, just before we do it,
I'll just say free cash flow is cash
generated by the business from selling
things that is extra cash. It's after
taxes, after all that good stuff. Money
that you can actually do something with.
And I know that we lived several years
in the period of where literally every
dollar that we generated had to go back
in to fund our growth. And I was I want
to start there. Like, how long did you
guys live in that era, Shawn? Yeah.
You know, I only joined Ridge in 2016.
So, I was 3 years into their history.
So, I can start talking about um the
agency days cuz I think a lot of people
listen to this and like I think our
average listener has like a seven-figure
e-commerce brand. We have a lot of
people have, you know, eight,
nine-figure e-commerce brands. We have a
lot of people who want to start brands.
And I always the advice is to start with
a service business because
the free cash flow from a service
business on day one is very high. It
could be 30% of uh of of accounts
receivable or whatever. Um and that's
just because there's no fixed costs. The
big problem in e-commerce in particular
is if you want revenue to go up, you
need more of whatever it is you sell.
You have to buy that somehow, right? The
reason why we always tell people not to
double is because you need twice as much
to double. Unless you're going to charge
2x for it and people want it that bad,
right? But that's like the
the classic scaling law in e-commerce is
you know, this year I'm going to sell a
million wallets. If I want to double
next year, I have to sell 2 million
wallets. Well, how am I going to get
that, right?
>> And you have to bet on the come. You
have to buy that inventory before you
know the sales are going to show up.
Yeah, yeah. Like, especially in our
business, is 60% of my sales happen now,
Q4, right? [laughter] So, it's like I
have to start working up my inventory
position because you can't just double
things overnight. It's a hard to make
stuff, right? So, in service businesses,
I mean, me and Connor in from 2015,
2016, and 2017 before the merger, we
probably each made like $45,000 a year,
right? And it was just because
we had no money, we had bad clients who
wouldn't pay us, whatever, right? When
we moved over to Ridge, um Ridge still
did not have a lot of money until like
2019. That was probably the first year
where we did like million-dollar
distributions. So, that's year six, year
six, year seven? Yeah, yeah. Roughly
year six into the business. Now, they
were
the when the guys were running it, they
said they were very happy if they could
split up $5,000 a day forever. They're
like, that'd be amazing. You know what I
mean? That was like that was like their
ultimate vision for the whole thing,
right? Um and it probably took until
2019 to get there. Jason, what about
you? Uh I know you joined Hexclad kind
of in flight, but
you were joining during hyper scaling.
Like, I was around the business from day
one and the journey was was a bit
diff- it's actually not dissimilar to a
lot of a lot of startups, but
uh you know, the founders put a bunch of
their own money in actually back in
2013, 2014 and started with a different
product, actually.
And that product actually got up to 5, 6
million in sales, but for a variety of
reasons, it was never going to be great
and they always had planned on having
multiple products. Like, that was always
the case.
And so, when the cookware hit,
um started selling well in late 2017,
um
that that's when the there was a real
business. And
it it wasn't until 2019
that uh people were really able to take
any money out and really pay themselves.
So, it was a really hard life
for these guys for a really long time
and people don't really know that part
of the story and I don't want to get
into too much detail cuz this is really
not up to me to say it, but these guys,
you know, they struggled and suffered
and that's why like I'm they deserve
everything they've gotten, you know,
because of the struggle. But in 20 in
2019, when the business was
um I would say closing in on
20 million in top line,
they were finally able to like,
you know, start taking some money out
and and it was
that was always their vision. Similar to
Shawn, like what Shawn said. I think the
vision was, "Hey, let's let's do it.
Let's create a nice business, you know,
20, 25 million. We can
we can throw off some really nice
profit, pay ourselves well." Um
obviously, they they way exceeded that,
but that was the that was the mentality
at the time and you know, it just went
really well.
It was roughly the same revenue size
when Ridge was able to pull out a
million-dollar distribution, right? It's
like I think
when 2019, we might I think we did
30-something million.
Some somewhere around there. That's that
sounds right.
Uh but we probably could have paid out
the distribution earlier, but we ran
into like a real cash flow crunch in
2017, 2018. We had absolutely no money.
Like, we had to pay a tax bill, we did
not do inventory planning right, and
there was a point where we had to put
money back into the business. Money
where we didn't have any money, right?
That was the capital call moment in this
business where it's like, "Okay,
everyone, does anyone have a 401k?"
Like, that's what we were looking for
like to try to put it into this
business. Um and then we were able to
get it all back the next year. Yeah,
well, one of the reasons why I wanted to
start here is that as you mentioned,
Shawn, the the people that listen to the
show come from a variety of different
backgrounds. Some of them are aspiring
to build an e-commerce business, some of
them are in the scaling process. They're
high six figures, they're mid seven
figures. And it is interesting. I think
we might have even been bigger than the
two of you because our margins were
lower before we did significant
distributions. We might have been more
like 50, 60 million. And it's So, like
if everybody listening,
expectation-wise,
if you've got a business that's growing
at a decent clip, you should just expect
like money can't come out until 20, 30,
40 million dollars in sales. And that's
a pretty sobering reality. If you've got
really high margins and maybe uh a lower
growth rate or because of the higher
margins, you don't have to reinvest as
much back in inventory, maybe you can
hit that earlier. But it's good to know
this at the outset. We're going to talk
a lot about, "Hey, what do you do with
cash when there's extra cash?" But the
reality is in e-commerce, because you
have to buy the inventory, it takes a
while. Like, I think both of you just
said, "Hey, it's around 5 years." I
think that was about our experience. And
these are really successful brands. Uh
that really caught me off guard, I
think, when I first got into e-commerce.
Just that
the amount of time it takes for an
e-commerce business to get to the scale
and maturity where like there's cash to
be had.
>> [snorts]
>> Yeah, and you know,
full transparency, you can make a salary
that the first 5 years, right? Like we
were paying ourselves 130 grand a year
or whatever. Which we felt like a lot of
money back then.
So like you can make a salary, but it's
in
it takes, you know, 5 to 5 to 7 years or
whatever until you start moving away
from just like having a job to actually
benefiting from like owning an asset,
right?
It just you have to plant those seeds
for a long time.
The last thing I want to say about this
is a lot of people love to hear this
point and then say that we're wrong for
X, Y, or Z reasons. And it's because you
can make a lot of money telling people
they can make money and you sell them
courses on it. And every 6 months one of
those course sellers gets busted for
some sort of fraud or scam and somebody
over. And
knock on wood no one on this podcast
that's happened to, right? It's because
we tell you exactly Yeah,
>> [laughter]
>> we tell you exactly what we think is
going to happen from lived experience.
And it's a very unsexy thing, which is
like yeah, you're going to work for 5
years and you might not make any money.
Which
>> [laughter]
>> that doesn't sell courses. Yeah, well,
you really you have to count the cost
before going all in on e-commerce. And
Sean, you mentioned this earlier, but
it's worth talking about here, I think,
that service businesses, there's some
pros and there's some real cons. And one
of the pros is that you can get money
out of that thing a lot quicker.
One of the cons is that you have a way
more we'll call it account receivable
risk when you run a service business
then. So like my the people that owe me
money are Amazon, Shopify, you know,
Walmart. They're going to pay their
bills. When you run a service business,
let's say you have a bunch of
seven-figure e-com sellers and then
liberation day happens, they all might
be like, hey, I just can't pay, you
know? And so you have a lot of risk of
your on your profits in a different way.
It might you might be able to get them
quicker, but you have more risk
on them when you do get them because of
the counterparties. Oh, yeah, like we
can talk me me and Taylor Holiday have
had massive debates about what's better.
And it just comes down to where you are
in your life. If you don't have money,
you should start a service business,
right? Like there's no more venture
capital coming into brands, nobody wants
to bet on them. Like you're signing
yourself up for a lot of pain and you
might have to put money into it. And if
you don't have that, bro, learn a skill
and then sell the skill. This is an
amazing time to be doing that, right?
Like learn AI consulting and then email
brands like Jason and tell them AI
consulting. And his email is
>> [laughter]
>> And as we've talked about like that's
great, especially if your income desires
are you know,
in the six figures, let's say. If you
want to really knock the cover off the
ball, it starts to get harder and harder
to do that in a service business. So
what I want to talk about is we we grew
our businesses to the point where they
were starting to generate real free cash
flow.
We're saying, hey, maybe this is 5, 6
years in. Revenue amounts will will
vary, but I think we're giving people a
feel for it takes a bit.
When you finally got to the point where
it's like, okay,
we've we've gotten money
we can actually make some decisions
with. Like a gun's not to our head, the
decisions aren't made for us.
One of the ways that you can reinvest in
the business is by dividing that up
between investing in your team,
investing in inventory, and investing in
new products. And I wanted to start
there. How do each of you think about
dividing between those different
buckets?
Well, we've we talked about this before
on the pod.
The business should always be fed first.
So if you have a business idea that you
think is worth pursuing, that always
gets top priority over everything else.
And that's because
>> Sean? Why is that? Yeah, it's because
you started a business because you can
compound returns at a higher rate than
the market. Taking money out of your
business instead of investing in your
business and putting it in the
treasuries, you're just leaving
potentially
50% annualized returns compounding out,
right?
The best growth engine in your life
should be your business. It's the
riskiest, right? I mean, maybe it's as
risky as, you know,
long call options on Trade Desk or
whatever, but it's still it's still a
very risky thing.
So you want to take some money out for
safety.
But the business should be able to
generate the best returns, right? It's
why private equity exists as an asset
class. It's because operating a thing
should get some sort of leverage on it
if you're good at it. And if you're
pulling cash flow out of your business,
you're pretty good at your
business, dude. You've made a thing that
pays you. It's it's going pretty
awesome. So the business should be fed
first.
And we don't have hard set in rules
being like, you know, 50% of free cash
gets distributed, right? We have
targets, we'd love to pay ourselves more
money, but it's like, look, if we have a
smoking idea that takes 99% of the cash
flow, that it's getting all of it. So I
want to drill down on that. Like as
you're saying, there's this delineation
between cash that comes in cash that
goes out and cash that stays in. But on
cash that stays in, you can either
funnel it into product dev, this is
molds, prototypes, stuff like that,
patent work, whatever. You can funnel it
to hiring and building out your team, or
you can funnel it into more inventory.
How do you think about breaking it down
between those different things, Sean?
Oh, yeah, and this is this is why I'm
probably a bad guest for this podcast,
man, because cuz the the the buckets are
not formed. It's like
it's we we look at free cash as one
giant bucket of money. And then it's
like whatever the best idea to get the
highest return gets the money until
we've exhausted what we think are the
best ideas and whatever's left over gets
distributed. So we're not being like,
okay, you know, there's $2 of profit, $1
goes out the door, $1 stays in, and then
the dollar that stays in goes to these
things. It's like
I have a breakout product right now. I'm
going to have to order a million of them
next year. That's going to be incredibly
expensive, but that's the highest growth
engine for this business. Putting that
money to order me a million of those
will get me more money in the future, so
we're pursuing that. That is where all
the free cash flow is going. Well, and
the way I experience it on the other
side of you, Sean, is that you are new
product is the absolute top tier of
reinvestment. That you're like, any
product idea that I think is viable or
that I think is scaling, I'm putting as
much cash into that as I feel like I
can, first and foremost. And then it
seems like team buildout happens later
based on like if you guys are scaling
and you feel the need, then you add to
that team bucket.
But that or the inventory bucket, but
first and foremost you're like, let's
just put everything we can at new
product that we think has a chance.
Well, and that's what happens right now
because that's where the growth is. It
could totally change in the future. Like
if next year
the all of the growth is happening by
investing in Open AI's new ad platform
or whatever, it's like that's where all
my money like if I don't need new
product to get growth and that's the new
channel that's going to work, I'll put
every dollar into that. But it's it's
assessing what we think is the highest
return profile and then putting a lot of
capital into that. Awesome. Jason, how
do you think about that? Look, a good
a good business at scale will generate
enough cash to grow
plus a return to shareholders.
You may want to over invest on
certain opportunities in the short term
that you feel really strong about
the return on those opportunities, but
the way I've always looked at it is
there's an EBITDA margin
that's that's required for a business to
be
conservatively to be properly managed.
You manage toward a margin
and anything above that margin
that margin should provide enough for
you to also invest in the business. So
like there's the P&L and then there's a
cash flow statement, but you know,
EBITDA is a kind of a P&L measure. And
you know, I think if you can if you can
run your business at a sufficient EBITDA
margin and that if you look at it from a
cash flow perspective,
you'll have cash going into growth
and you'll still be able to maintain the
margin and then you'll have cash coming
out.
Um
And and still maintain the margin. In in
sometimes you you might have the
opportunity to lever up and invest more.
Yeah, we're going to ask I'm going to
ask you about that here in a second.
>> margin at
like margin at each stage of the
business, too, right? Like early on, you
you probably will be willing to have a
lower margin because you think you will,
you know, at scale you will find
operational efficiencies, whether it's
whether it's grow, you know, or or gross
margin efficiencies or marketing
efficiencies. But, you know, another
measure to look at in the tech world
used to be the rule of 40.
Where a good a good SaaS company, and I
think it kind of applies to almost any
business, maybe at different levels, but
the rule of 40, right? Your top line
growth rate plus your
EBITDA margin percentage should combined
equal 40. And that is that is a good
measure or a good north star for your
business. So
if I'm growing 40%, I could break even
on a P&L basis, right? If I'm growing
50%, I could even be negative because
and again, maybe not exactly
applicable to a consumer business which
has to buy inventory and stuff like
that, but these are like these are good
rules of thumb and I think there's
there're going to be different
differences in in every case, but you
got to start like with the North Star
somewhere and decide uh can use business
judgment
whether or not to deviate from it.
Okay, so I'm going to push you some more
on it. When you're doing your planning
for the upcoming year, when you and
Danny are looking at how the P&L is
going to change over the upcoming year,
how do you think about the cash that's
being reinvested in the business to
produce some of that growth? I think
it's a helpful idea by the way, the
EBITDA margin plus growth
idea. The first you were the first
person I heard that from, but I found it
to be helpful.
But as you're trying to make decisions,
how do you think about okay, how much of
this money are we going to put towards
team growth, how much of it are we going
to put towards buying more inventory for
say international markets or a new
retail opportunity or a new product
line, and how much are we going to spend
in just like R&D product, which is
another thing you guys have been doing?
How have you made the nuts and bolts
decisions about how much you put in each
of those categories? Yeah, look, this is
this is a lot of art and science
combined. We know we our decisions are
all based on how do we continue to grow
this business because we're a pretty big
business now. So, that's always the
case. Like what do we have to do to
maintain a minimum growth rate and a
minimum amount EBITDA margin and then as
as other opportunities arise, like if
you have a big winner somewhere, like
Sean's got one right now, it's like
okay, we can press we can gas this here
cuz we know. So,
um
I'm I'm not a I'm not like a big
believer in two in too many rules of
thumb, too many heuristics because like
so much of this is subjective and what's
going to happen on a
you know, for with our businesses is
going to be different than than any
other business. Everyone's different,
but I think we um we just managed toward
those
those pieces. How are we going to
continue to grow our top line? We want
to grow the enterprise value of Hexclad,
right? That's fundamentally we are
making decisions. Um we're not kids, you
know, we're in a fifth in our 50s. So,
we're looking at everything that we look
at
doing is based on is this going to
increase the long-term enterprise value
of our business and if that happens, we
know we are going to make enough money
to keep the the shareholders happy. So,
what I'm really hearing from you guys is
there's not really hard and fast rules
or like necessarily even a heuristic
other than
what is the thing that we think grows
enterprise value the most, that has the
most heat on it, invest in that, and
whatever that looks like. Whether that's
inventory, whether that's piling into
product, whether that's adding people to
support it, you just you and and it
could look very different year to year.
Yeah, I was going to say, you know, in
our business it's probably product or
marketing. It's like, you know, and I
want to talk through the
the typical P&L for a brand to get to
that rule of 40, but like
you
people cost should be smaller than both
of those buckets. Like people cost
should be smaller than product and be
smaller than marketing. So, like you
really out of those three buckets, one
of one of them's way bigger than the
other one and you're going to put all
your money into that one.
Um
Yeah. Well, one of them's easier to
spend up. I mean, I think one of the
reasons on the people side is that um
you know, we're we're not building large
language models where, you know, we're
hiring people on billion-dollar
contracts like Zuckerberg is. So, it
it's a lot easier to add people when you
need them because the skill set's not
super specific. So, that makes a ton of
sense.
Hey, you know what's important to your
business? Understanding it. That's where
Saras Analytics comes in. Jason, what if
I told you that our margins yesterday
were about 30%, but like, you know,
there's a big difference between saying
you're about 30% and saying you're
27.4%,
right? Like that that level of precision
can only happen if your data is rock
solid and in one place where you can
actually pull it from. That's where
Saras Analytics comes in for Ridge. So,
every single day I'm going in there, I'm
looking at my contribution margin, I'm
looking at my sales breakdown, my sales
by product type, and it really just
starts shedding a light into like the
the black holes of your business. Jason,
what have you gotten out of Saras
Analytics? Honestly, everything is at my
fingertips. Our dashboards pull in from
everywhere, from Shopify, from Amazon,
from our ERP,
from Costco, every single channel, and
we go to Saras pulse and we get our
daily contribution margin reporting, we
get all of our marketing metrics by
channel, by category, even down to the
SKU. Everything is pulled in
automatically. I get an email report in
the morning, I go check things during
the day. My entire team lives in this
thing.
>> Yeah, and everyone knows the revenue
yesterday. If you ask any brand, they'll
tell you what their revenue was.
Maybe 20% of brands can tell you their
contribution margin and about 0% of
brands can tell you their profit for
yesterday. And if you're not watching
your profit on a daily or at least
weekly basis, it can just get get out
from under you. You know, to the Saras
team's credit, we have a daily growth
dashboard sheet from
probably 2018 and they were able to
import all of that data. And the reason
to do that is eventually sheets just
breaks. Like we end up having three or
four full-time people like maintaining
this giant sheet. And Saras Analytics,
by putting it into an actual database
with actual data connectors and
pipelines, it just makes it more
future-proof. I'm going to give you guys
a real world use case. So, I just had to
set 2026 financial budgets. Saras
Analytics made that data available in
four clicks compared to 40 hours. It
used to take me probably literally a
week or two to like figure out what my
projections for the next year could be.
With Saras Analytics, I got it done in
an afternoon. So, it's like AI for your
business knowledge. And if you want to
check out Saras Analytics, that is s a r
a s and see how daily precise data can
transform your profitability.
All right, Jason, so you guys have used
debt to pull more cash out of the
business. You've done a dividend recap.
How did you decide to do that? We
decided to do that because
we were seeing all this profit on the
P&L
and seeing all of our cash going into
inventory and taxes and
um
we've we have experience I have
experience doing large-scale financings.
As a banker, I've seen people lever up
to seven times EBITDA.
And we kind of all sat around the table
and said, "Hey, at a two times EBITDA,
that's at at the current in the current
rate environment with the tax
deductibility of interest, we were we
would we look at it as taking a little
money out earlier um rather than having
to wait, especially because we were
going through some really high growth
stages where we were tying up a lot in
inventory. We're at a we're at like a
more moderate growth stage now, really
solid, but moderate. And so things are a
little bit more predictable, but in our
case it was sort of taking money out
from the future knowing that um you
know, we're basically like look, public
company CEOs, they always they borrow
against their equity, you know, like
rather than selling. It's a little
there's a little bit of that, too. It's
like, "Okay, how do we borrow against
our equity to enjoy our lives because
we're not a bunch of people in our 20s
or 30s." [clears throat]
>> of money is real, right? Like I was
telling this to somebody the other day.
I was saying like the the way that I'm
wired, the way that I know you guys are
wired is hey, I'm willing to play the
marshmallow test game. I'm willing to
have less today to have more tomorrow,
but there's one like really important
characteristic that either makes that
point of view like really wise or
incredibly stupid and and here it is. Do
you ever eat the marshmallow? Because if
you never eat the marshmallow
marshmallow, then you're just lying to
yourself. You're just kind of constantly
pushing off into the future a day that
never comes.
And like your point, Jason, like hey, at
some point you've built a really
valuable company and you want to enjoy
it. Sean, your point about compounding
money makes sense, but again, if you
never use that money, who cares how big
you compound it to?
Yeah, like do you want to be Christian
Bale in The Machinist, just starving to
death, but you have like infinite
marshmallows, or do you want to just,
you know, eat a couple of them every
once in a while?
>> It's like when you want it's like when
you go to buy a house. I talk to a lot
of people about this, like going to buy
real estate and they're they're trying
to like calculate some ROI and I'm like
my guy, there is call there's a value to
you living someplace that you have makes
you happy. You know, and you can't do
that. So, you know, just like stretch
just like stretch on, you know, you
should stretch on that because it's it's
going to make you happy. It's kind of
it's kind of the same thing. Where are
you in your life, you know, if you're in
your 20s and early 30s, you you should
be grinding hard so that when you're in
your 40s, you get to enjoy it. And then
when you're in your 50s, you enjoy it
more. And then when you're 60s, you can
just chill. That's the JP plan, anyway.
The JP plan, I love it. Trademark.
[snorts] So, one interesting thing, we
we work with
uh Morgan Chase and we were talking with
our our group and and I don't know if
they were talking about this being true
regionally or nationally, but I think
they meant nationally. They were telling
us that another player in our space was
trying to do a dividend recap and that
they didn't think it was going to get
done. And then they made an offhand
comment to our CFO Jeff that they had
not done a single dividend recap this
year or maybe it was this year post
liberation day. Like that So, like the
idea of dividend recap is like, "Oh, you
know, we have stability in our earnings
and we're going to kind of pull that
forward into today."
Well, not surprisingly, the banks are
not really keen on giving that to just
about anybody right now because it's
like who knows what the environment is
even 12 months from now.
That's a good point. You know, and what
I've seen in the market too talk
talking to banks. Uh, you know, we have
a syndicate of six banks.
And just with the environment the way it
is
Um, it it yeah, it might be tougher
right now. Luckily, we're not looking to
do it right now, but that's why I tell
people take the money. You know, when
there's a deal there take the money cuz
things can change. You know, we did ours
and like whenever there's a deal on the
table, I'm I'm always push push push get
it done because you just have no idea
like what externality is going to kick
in and and mess up your deal. So, always
just you know, take the money. Well, and
I I think you've rubbed on me some on
this Jason like I I've always been like
I know keep all the chips on the table
and now I'm like
you should take at least some chips off
the table. When somebody wants to give
you a big valuation, when somebody
writes it wants to write a big check in,
you should think about it. Yeah, it's
nice to own 100% of something, but also
like you can't pay for your trip to
Disneyland with you know, shares of your
company stock. And so like when you get
an opportunity to get some liquidity, I
just am kind of more of the opinion that
you do it in moderation, which we're
going to get back to this later when we
talk about like how we invest our
personal money, but like generally like
really big dramatic actions have a lot
of opportunity to go against you. But
somebody wants to give you a big number
valuation for your equity or something
today like you never you you've never
gone broke or gone bankrupt taking a
little bit of chips off the table.
Yeah. Now, Mike, it seems like you're
more structured than us when it comes to
deploying capital. So, maybe we should
tell the audience what like the the
structured system of
filtering capital through your business
is. Yeah. So, the the way that I think
about it is just similar to you two.
There is
a hierarchy and I think product if
you're running an e-commerce business, a
consumer brand
you really have to invest in product
first. And if you have good viable
product ideas, you should be investing
in them. One of the things that I think
I have learned
that I would do a little bit differently
and and we'll maybe talk more about
things we would do differently here in a
bit, but
I
we we've put money in product
historically and we've been decent about
investing there, but I would have put
even more because when you like let's
say you've got an idea for a new water
bottle and you're like we want to try
and do a lid that works like this.
But we're not exactly sure if it'll work
or how it'll come out. We've got two or
three ideas. The way that we would do it
in the past is I would allocate enough
money to make them the mold and the
tooling for one of those lids.
I think if I could go back and do it
over, one of the things I would do
different is I would be like no, I
actually want to have enough money that
I can make three tools and maybe I don't
even use two of them, but that I know I
get the best product out of it. And
product is like such an asymmetric lever
and so I'm similar to you guys in that
that like
hey, if we're going to put money port
towards product, um, if we're going to
put money towards anything, we're going
to start with product. But I'm I'm
probably we're probably more structured
in how we think about people because we
want to have low turnover. We think
that's, you know, a formula for
outperformance. So, we're pretty
intentional about thinking about hey,
where's our overhead as a percentage of
revenue, where do we think it can go,
who are the people you know, how do we
continue to invest in our team so that
we have low turnover and that we keep
all of our top performers.
And that's usually going to be I mean at
our scale
like I don't know, that might be a
million dollars of growth in a year or
something a million and a half. I I'd
have to look at the numbers.
And so we but then the other thing that
we have historically invested money in
is growing through inventory. So, a real
simple example here is that uh, when
you're selling in say
Walmart or Target
there will always be one or two things
of your new kind of set every year that
just pops off unexpectedly and sells
more than you expect. And so your
options are buy everything pretty lean
and then be surprised and be out of
stock for a couple months on one of your
best things or you buy five six months
of cover to for your initial set with
Walmart and Target and even if something
pops off at a level that you weren't
expecting, you're able to get all those
sales. Um, and so like but it ties up
more capital. And that's a really So,
we've seen quite a few examples in our
business where it's like yeah if we're
willing to have another $500,000 sitting
inventory, we will get more sales off
that. Now, it might not be as high a
return as, you know, some other things,
but like that's that's a good way to
invest capital. What I think I've come
around to and one of the things that got
me thinking about the subject is
I think as a shareholder, I should have
done more demanding capital to flow back
out of the business. I think I've shared
the hat of like I'm the biggest
shareholder and I'm the CEO. And so I've
had this temptation to like just be like
no, run it run it back. Run it back.
Keep all the chips on the table. And if
you do that, eventually the business
starts investing cash in lower and lower
return ways. I think it might I think we
might have even invested some cash in
negative return on investment ways where
it's like hey, you already got four
water bottle listings on Amazon. A fifth
one isn't going to be incremental. It it
might be a negative return on capital
for you to do that.
And so I'm more I'm I'm more interested
in this idea of like running a business
well is this balance of how you think
about cash and even to some extent as a
shareholder having good expectations
about how much cash flows out of the
business. That holds management
accountable to make good investment
decisions if that makes sense. Yeah, and
there's a there's a rule you hear in
private equity when they hire CEOs is
that like the CEO shouldn't be the owner
because
um
it makes a CEO's life easier to have
more money in the bank and it makes an
owner's life harder to have more money
in the bank in the business's bank,
right? So, like the CEO will always be
way more conservative. And I'm I'm like
this. I'm like I don't want to take
money out of my business cuz like what
if I need it, right? Like but the
reality is you'll figure out what to do
when you need it and it just it's like a
it's like a safety blanket just keeping
cash in the bank, right? Where yeah, if
you have a more demanding shareholder,
you would just always be be pushing
money out of the business. I think
that's what HexClad does, but does
better than Ridge. Yeah, HexClad's been
good about this and I I think you're
right, uh, Shawn absolutely that like
there's advantages and disadvantages of
sharing the shareholder hat and the
management hat. Whereas like in all
corporations, these are going to be more
split up and one of the upsides is you
don't have an unreasonable shareholder
like like liberation day happens and
it's like well, you know what? There
needs to be no capital flowing out of
the business right now. We need to
figure out what the heck is going on.
And then we'll get to it. Whereas, you
know, if if ownership was totally
divorced from management, they might be
like I don't care. We want the dividends
to keep flowing.
But the other side of that is that you
can start to think about all of the
capital and all the cash flow of the
business much more like an operator or a
manager than a shareholder and then, you
know, what you're really doing is you're
devaluing the company and devaluing the
shares when you do that.
All right, folks. This episode is
brought to you by our friends at
Northbeam, the marketing attribution
platform that every smart performance
team should be using. Northbeam just
dropped something game-changing. It's
called clicks plus deterministic views,
the world's first deterministic
view-through attribution model.
Well, why does that matter? Well,
because traditional one-day click
attribution is completely skewed towards
bottom of funnel campaigns. It's like
giving all the credit to the player who
makes the last shot and ignoring
everyone who passed the ball to get
there. You know the story, your TikTok
and CTV ads are building awareness,
driving engagement, lifting overall
revenue across every channel.
But your dashboard says they're doing
nothing. Meanwhile, Google Ads looks
like a hero because that's where people
click last. That's the click-only trap
and it's one of the biggest myths in
performance marketing. It creates a
vicious cycle where you cut top of
funnel spend, your awareness dries up
and performance tanks. Northbeam's new
model fixes that. Clicks plus
deterministic views actually shows you
which ad impressions drove conversions.
Not guesses, not modeled correlations,
verified data.
They pull direct impression level data
from Meta, TikTok, Snap, Pinterest, and
CTV and match it deterministically using
real identifiers, order IDs, hashed
emails, logins, not cookies or fuzzy
logic. It's precise, transparent, and
built to close the gap between awareness
and conversion. You'll finally see those
mystery revenue spikes tied back to
upper level funnel campaigns that
actually deserve the credit. That's the
Northbeam edge, clarity, accuracy, and
confidence in your budget decisions.
You'll know which channels are really
moving the needle and which ones are
just taking the credit. And yeah, the
biggest brands are already using it.
Manscaped, Dollar Shave Club, HexClad,
Grinds, and many more.
So, if you want to see what real
deterministic view attribution looks
like, go to northbeam.io/demo
to book a demo and tell them that we
sent you because if you're still flying
blind on clicks only, you're missing the
full picture.
I I'm I'm really kind of I I guess I'd
ask this question now like based on what
we're talking about. How Jason, you said
this like you should run it at a good
EBITDA margin, but you should also the
business should also be able to spit out
cash. How much cash should your business
be able to spit out? Obviously I'm not
I'm not looking for a number, but like
how do you think about that? What's the
bar you hold Hexclad to of hey, you
should be able to produce this much. Is
it is that and is that one of the
reasons why you did a dividend recap?
Because then it's like hey, you have to
produce this much. The production is
it's it depends on it just depends on
your growth rate, right? Because
businesses require
working capital to operate and require
investment capital to grow.
And so um
I think it's it's hard to put numbers on
it, but like
you know, when we were growing when we
were growing really fast, we just real
you know, we just realized that there's
there's a a capital a level of capital
investment that we were going to have to
do
um and we were but we still need to be
satisfied with the ability to take money
out of the business. And uh again, we
will only do it up to a certain level.
And like we're not going to over lever
the business, but
also when you look at companies like
like ours, any of ours and when you look
at M&A today,
you're going to have private equity guys
in the equation. And more than likely
those private equity guys are going to
want to use some debt.
So that was a one of the
one of the things that hit us
that like the light bulb went off to
you know, the guys you know, I get it
because I've been a banker, but
these guys want to buy your company with
with debt that they're going to use you
know, that they're going to basically
take based on your cash flow. They want
to juice those returns, maybe. Lever up.
Yeah, let me just like I'll I'll let you
clarify, but I'll I'll just say like so
in our case, it was like yeah, you know
what? We don't particularly want to sell
the whole thing, you know, but so but
the dividend recap is like well, here's
a little way for us to do our own kind
of like mini LBO. So I I look at the
dividend recap more like um
mini LBO.
>> like selling a part of your future. It's
selling a part of the business when you
do a dividend recap. So it was like you
guys taking some chips off the table,
right? Yeah, and you know, just because
we're an educational podcast, so I just
want to you know, step in and let's
educate some listeners. When you have
profit, okay, profit is at the end of
the the rule of 40, okay? You do all
this you get this profit number, okay?
Taxes take a piece out of it and then
you have free cash. Then it's like free
cash could either go into distributions,
working capital, or investment capital.
And at some point, maybe you'll get your
money out of working capital, but
usually that balloons over time, right?
Yeti has 500 million dollars in working
capital because it has a huge inventory
position.
>> either you liquidate the business, you
have a going out of business sale and
that's how you get the working capital
out, or you sell the company. That's it.
Like there's no other way to get it out,
right?
>> Right, right. Because cuz when you sell
it, you you sell it working capital's on
the balance sheet. So they they will pay
you for your cash in your business.
They'll pay you your inventory value. So
eventually maybe there's some way to get
it out, but usually there comes to be
some sort of a carve out where you have
to give them some sort of working
capital in a bank account so they don't
have to pay your people the first day or
whatever. But anyway, you have profit, a
big balloon full of profit. You're going
to put it across these buckets. And it's
like how do you decide what goes into
distributions to my pocket, so it's
leaving the business, so it's a one-way
door. It does hopefully doesn't come
back in. What goes into working capital
so you can grow next year? And then what
goes into these flyer investment ideas,
right? That's what that's what we're
talking about. Uh so everyone has way
more money than they think. Let's just
tied up in inventory and cash and paying
your people and whatever else. That's
why e-commerce in particular, we're
going to bring it up all the time, you
can have a 50 million dollar a year
business and you can make 700 grand a
year.
>> [laughter]
>> You you think you should be rich. You're
like oh my god, like I have a 50 I'm a
50 millionaire. No, you're not. You have
about 700 grand, right? That's just the
reality. But people people need to
realize that
businesses require capital. It's it the
word capital is in there, right? Working
capital is is capital. So at some point
you put cash in the business, cash goes
on the balance sheet, it's a short-term
asset. You use that cash to buy
inventory and that that's working
capital. Like that's you just you need a
basic basic base amount of working
capital to run your business. And when
uh back in the day in the early e-com
days, when everyone was either in some
kind of like affiliate business or drop
shipping business,
you really didn't have to put
put up so much working capital and then
This is why the drop shipping bros pop
up every so often. It's like and the
reason why drop shipping seems
attractive is that if you never take
possession of the inventory, then you
never have to take on the working
capital. This is also why those
businesses don't ever last because
>> Or scale, yeah. Some yeah, or scale.
Because what happens is somebody's like
well, if I invested some capital here
and held the inventory, then I can smoke
these drop shipping bros and that's what
it ends up happening. So like there's
there's a lot of this also has to do
with manufacturers. And remember, your
manufacturing partners, they have
working capital in the exact same way.
And some of their working capital is
that they have to own like, you know,
stainless steel and equipment and all
the stuff. And some of their working
capital needs are that they have to
finance your growth. Like so they have
receivables just like you have
receivables. Our manufacturer has
receivables and
we probably have I don't know, five or
10 million dollars worth of credit that
we take advantage of. Guess where that
capital's coming from? It's their
working capital. Totally. And the
reality is if you're still doing
business in China, a lot of people got
totally screwed by liberation day. Not
because, you know, orders slowed down,
but because people just didn't pay for
their
So like that's a real issue right now
happening at factories and there's going
to be a lot of factory closures
because
the now the factory's stuck with a bunch
of products nobody wants, right?
>> is why working capital also gives you an
advantage from negotiating. Like when
you're well capitalized, you can go to a
factory and say I should pay less. And
they should say well, this is the price
and say yeah, maybe that's the price
you're giving everybody else, but you
know what? They are much bigger risks to
not pay than I am. I'm going to pay less
than them because I'm well capitalized.
And they'll say well, you know, that's a
good point. Okay.
And and so like when you have a lot of
capital in the business, this is the
argument for keeping your business well
capitalized, there will be opportunities
left and right that your or you know,
like you don't have to finance as much
of your receivables, for example. While
you're paying the bank to finance your
receivables. There's a thousand
different ways that this plays out. Um
and and this is also the reason why it
just takes a while before money coming
out of the business makes sense because
putting money back in the piggy bank of
your business is the right financial
move for the first several years for for
almost every business. I think we should
define rich buyout. We've talked about
it before, but if you're a new listener
to the Operators podcast, like,
subscribe, comment how much you love
Shawn as you figured operator. Um
when private equity comes to buy your
business, okay? They're going to give
you a check. Let's say they're going to
give you a 100 million dollars for your
business. They're going to buy 80% of
your business at a 100 million dollar
valuation. So they're actually you're
actually only getting 80 million
dollars. They're going to roll over 20%,
right? You're going to continue to own
that.
And you're like great, I would love 80
million dollars. This is fantastic.
Let's say you have 10 million dollars in
EBITDA. So 10 million dollars in EBITDA
times 10, you get a 10x multiple, okay?
When it comes time to do the deal,
they're only going to come out of pocket
maybe 40 million dollars, okay? Where
does the other 40 million dollars come
from? Your business that you owned 100%
of is going to be responsible for the 40
million dollars in debt. The business is
going to take out the debt or the debt
will be taken out and insured by the
business and then given to you, right?
So now you're going to own 20% of your
business, but now it has 40 million
dollars in debt on it. What Jason did is
he cut out the private equity guys and
he's like I'll just put debt on my
business and then take the to take the
debt into my pocket. That's that's a
dividend recap and that's a leveraged
buyout. So it's like the reason why
private equity can offer the highest
prices is because they are putting debt
onto your asset that you you owned
before they did that.
And this is also why private equity
takes things that once were awesome and
makes them not awesome.
>> [laughter]
>> Also because like
>> Sometimes, yeah, sometimes.
>> Sometimes I mean, not always. Like
obviously it works sometimes, but
there's a great meme. Maybe we'll have
to find it and throw it up on the
screen, but like where it's like a
Scooby-Doo meme and it's like, you know,
what made this thing that was once
awesome not awesome? And then they pull
off the mask and it's it's private
equity. And so like when you know, when
you take on debt, like there's there's
bills that have to be paid and so uh
this actually kind of going back to our
conversation with cash, well, when you
have debt, the first thing in the stack
is actually paying your debtors. So you
don't go bankrupt. And so like
investment actually comes after paying
debt. And that's one of the reasons why
you want to be careful with that is that
it reduces like your options, reduces
the choices that you can make. But uh
it's super interesting how you guys
handled it, Jason. I mean, one of the
reasons why this is top of mind, we had
our owner meeting
I guess two weeks ago and uh
I just said listen,
here's what I want going forward. Uh
I'm going to set a number.
It's an eight-figure number. We are
going to do this much in dividends every
year.
And then I want to find a way to
reinvest everything over that number.
And and in some ways, the number was a
little bit arbitrary. I mean, it kind of
makes sense for where we are in terms of
our EBITDA and stuff, but I was just
like this is the number.
As a shareholder,
I need to be able to plan on this
number. And we are going to hit this
number and then we'll reinvest
everything that we can over and above
that. We're getting to the scale where I
don't even know if we can reinvest
everything over and above that number,
but I need to be able to plan. And
because like one and and like maybe we
can transition to like the personal
piece of this is that I'm really curious
how you guys handle the cash that comes
out of the business because it's
actually a lot more simple when you're
reinvesting cash in the business than
when the business starts to spit out
cash.
Because
uh you can use it on you can consume it
or you can reinvest it and then when you
reinvest it I'm curious how you guys
reinvest it. So, let's let's start
there. Now that you guys both live the
good life, you're on easy street, your
business is
10 years in, you survived the e-com
uh
you know the e-com challenge and you now
actually make cash from your business.
Your business kicks out cash. How do you
think about using that? Jason, how do
you use the money that comes out of the
business?
>> mine's an easy mine's an easy one. I
think Sean's is going to be more
interesting than mine cuz he's younger.
Um
but
honestly my my goal is to just like have
a good set up for the rest of my days
and so like I've been investing a lot in
my own personal real estate so that I
can enjoy my life later and make sure
that I have enough
you know, that my kids need it.
Um
that you know, that's that's kind of
like the way I look at it. You know,
Sean's life is going to change a little
bit soon but you know, it's pretty
um
I I'm investing in I'm doing the things
that just are going to make me happy,
you know, cuz I'm 54 years old. So,
you're you're more focused on
consumption. You did mention your kids
like how have you thought about how much
of that cash flows down to your kids?
Yeah, look at my kids have been I paid
for their college, you know, they're
both really great kids and they have
direction in life which I'm very
fortunate in it. So, so that part is
good. I managed to pay for everything
for them and they work hard, you know,
son's got a good job, daughter's
graduating from university this year.
So, you know, I want them I want them to
I worked really hard to get to where I
am. My parents were great parents but
they didn't have a ton of money
and and my kids actually, you know, they
grew up in
uh
you know, middle class like they did
it's not like we were we did a lot. So,
I want them to have that that mentality
of actually putting in the work too but
I I want to make sure they have a good
you know, they going to have a good
safety net behind them as well.
Operators, Black Friday Cyber Monday's
coming up. Is your SMS list ready? If
not, get on Postscript. They're helping
us drive 14% more email sign ups through
their better opt-ins. They're helping us
get 6% more SMS subs every single day
because they have perfected the art of
pop-ups. You need to build your list,
you have to nurture your list, you have
to take care of your list. Postscript is
the best at that. They're the number one
name in SMS. It's a number one revenue
driver. We are excited and ready to take
advantage of all of the lists we've
built all year, okay?
Postscript has the best opt-in of all
time. It is single sign-in, password
auto fill right on your phone and we're
going to get probably another 100,000
people to sign up between now and the
end of the year. We're going to use
those people we're going to use SMS to
nurture them through the funnel. It's an
amazing tool. I love it. Make sure
you're ready for Black Friday Cyber
Monday. Postscript is here to help guide
you through everything that you need
when it comes to SMS. More opt-ins, more
list building. Make sure you don't look
like an amateur this BFCM. Use
Postscript. Tell them Sean sent you.
Tell them the operator sent you.
Postscript will audit your SMS program
for free and show you how to scale fast
before Black Friday Cyber Monday hits.
When we talk about list growth, that's
what you have to use before, during and
after Black Friday. You want serious
gains, you want Postscript. Thank you
for supporting the podcast. Thank you
for being here.
It's interesting Jason one of the
reasons why I asked the stuff about
kids.
One of my projects I would say over the
last three or four years is that I am
fairly I'm very interested, borderline
obsessed, with talking to families that
have had kind of generational wealth and
I I'm really curious about how do you
manage
high net worth in a way that doesn't
screw up your kids or your grandkids.
And so one of like the ways that I've
done that is I've I've started to get to
know these families that have had that
kind of wealth and what I look for is I
look for
third generations that aren't screwed up
and then I'm like, okay, now I want to
talk to the grandparents.
And I want to understand like what did
you do? How did you handle things with
your kids? What did you pass down that
led to you've at least got grandkids
that aren't totally screwed up by all
the money?
And one of the things that's been really
interesting is that there are a lot of
different approaches. The other group of
people that I'll talk to about this,
wealth managers are super interesting to
just pick their brain because this is
all they do. They deal with families
that have really high net worth and
they've seen all the horror stories and
uh so anyway like
I don't know, it's interesting. I I
asked one wealth manager I was just
like, hey
if you had really high net worth, what
would you do when it came to your kids?
And she was like, I wouldn't give them
anything
based on everything I've seen. Now, not
everybody comes out that way. I've
talked to other people that are just the
opposite where they're like, hey, when
my kids got into the 30 their 30s and I
saw that they were going to be
responsible, I started moving assets
over.
Um so I've seen a really wide spectrum
of people doing it different ways and it
working out okay. Uh but it also like
really gives you pause when you talk to
these type of people because you realize
that like, yeah, man, the money has an
opportunity to really make my kids'
lives better but it also has an
opportunity to make their lives
quite a bit worse, you know? And there's
plenty of those stories if you're not
careful. Yeah, um dude, it's it's
something I'm thinking about.
Uh I plan on giving my kids no money or
at least telling them they're not going
to get any money.
You know, I and I think Jason has a
correct approach. You should pay for
unlimited college. If they want to go be
doctors
and you have the means, student loans
are a killer of my generation. I posted
on Twitter recently that I think there's
a lack of 25 to 35-year-old
entrepreneurs. You guys are killing it.
People look up to you guys. You guys are
Gen Xers, right? Like it's like this
this people around my age, I think we
got screwed the worst by the 2008
housing crisis cuz then like there was a
recession. You're coming out of the job
market. I graduated high school in 2012
or whatever.
Uh but like it was very hard to get jobs
if you're a little bit older than me.
And a lot of people came out of college
couldn't figure out and then we also had
the highest tuition ever.
So, I think like there's like a double
whammy over my generation. So, Yeah,
it's a terrible the system really
screwed over a lot of people and that's
why
like let's take a world what's not not
quite politics but like social
um situation in the United States right
now. You have all these people with
great with huge amounts of loans that
were told go to college and you'll and
and take out loans and you'll find
something to do to make that money back
and and it has not happened be and and
therefore these people don't have a
stake in the current system and that's
why you're seeing someone like the the
guy who might win for mayor of New York
and and people supporting what like a
real capitalist person would think is
like a really crazy and ideas that
people get is is it's fundamentally
because they don't have a stake in the
current system. Like they're so screwed.
There's so many people that are just so
screwed. It's it's crazy.
Yeah, I read I read something
interesting yesterday about gold and
they were making the point that it's
just very unprecedented for gold to be
appreciating this much versus almost
every currency. It basically shows a
loss of confidence in the current
financial system and that if you go back
historically like over centuries and
look for any of the other times where it
has gotten this out of whack. I mean,
you're talking about things like the
French Revolution, you know, like major
disruptive events in history because and
the point they were making is that
typically when you see gold go this kind
of vertical
it's because the rich start to acquire
it and hoard it to try and kind of find
protection in it as an asset class but
that that's usually a sign that it's
about to go really badly because it's
it's also a sign of disenfranchisement
among lower income levels. And to your
point, Jason,
clearly we're we had a period where
there was like this yeah, hey, if you're
you're a good kid and you get into a
college and you get a degree, you know,
you're going to be able to go buy your
house and and do these things and like
then a bunch of people realize like,
hey, that's not actually possible.
Um that that that version of the dream
was not actually possible and so it's
pretty frustrating if you think you're
playing the marshmallow test and you're
not really. There's no marshmallow at
the end. Oh dude, yeah. So, I have I
have a friend. His dad went to UCLA but
UCLA in the 70s was a lot cheaper and
easier to get into than UCLA today. And
then his son worked his ass off to get
into UCLA and then it's like for what?
It's it's you know, if you want to live
in LA you and you make $100,000 a year
which is an amazing salary, you will
never own a home, right? Because every
home's $2 million. Um
but look, and America's actually better
off than everybody else. Look up the
housing pricing index. So, it's like
average incomes in an area to the
average housing price.
Europe's
Canada's Asia's crazy, dude. Houses in
Shanghai cost 30x the average income per
year. And in LA it's
>> It's like the craziest. If you think
you've seen a housing bubble, you
haven't seen anything compared to China
and what they did.
Yeah, so I I know what's going to
happen. Going grounding us back in this
conversation, I think Jason did the
correct thing. If you have the means,
paying for your kids' college because
that was the path everyone had to be on
until this year basically, right? So,
thank you for not, you know, saddling
your kids with a bunch of debt. Uh
but yeah, I I definitely I'm going to
tell my kids they're not getting
anything cuz I want them to work their
ass off like I had to. And then and then
if they get something when I die, good
for them, right? Uh Well, there's a
pretty good principle here which is like
when you when you take on debt and you
don't know your future earnings, that is
a really precarious place to be. I mean,
it's precarious for a business. Like
when you're like, "Yeah, I'm going to
take on debt, and I'm going to run up my
credit cards, and I'm going to borrow as
much as I can. I don't have product
market fit yet, but I'm going to find
it." It's like, "Well, good freaking
luck." Like there's a really good chance
that that story doesn't go well for you.
It's the same thing where it's like,
"Hey, I'm going to go to whatever
Vanderbilt, and I'm going to study 15th
century literature at $35,000 a year,
but it's all going to work out somehow."
And it's like, "Well, no." I think
everybody realizes like that's not the
case anymore. You should not go into
debt to do that. There's very few
degrees where it it feels stable enough
like I'll put it this way. Would either
of you advise one of your kids to go
into debt to get a computer science
degree
today?
Well, I wouldn't advise my kids to go
into debt for any education. You know,
my my wife became an accountant. She
went to Northridge. It was $6,000 a
year. And that was 5 years ago or 10
years ago. Like like you can get those
tuitions, but it's at schools nobody
wants to go to, right? And I had a very
untraditional education. Like I was out
of school by the time I was 16, and I
had to go to like School of Hard Knocks,
baby. Yeah, yeah. I had I had to I had
to go to internet school cuz I was a
troublemaker. So like but look,
untraditional outcomes Sorry,
untraditional education leads to
untraditional outcomes. Me and McCoy,
the CMO of Portland Leather Goods, had
the basically the same upbringing. And
two guys from towns are running awesome
brands. So I think it it can work out,
man. Is e-com like the the digital
juvie? Is that like
>> [laughter]
[snorts]
>> for all the delinquent ones we just
gravitate towards e-com?
Yeah, basically, man.
Um
No, but Do you guys think about
diversification when money comes out?
Are you like, "Hey,
almost all my net worth is in this like
company. I need to buy some I need to
own some stuff other than like stock in
my company."
Yeah, I mean, I have a wealth manager,
so I put
70% of everything into that. Then what's
left over,
I put
10% into
uh just like S&P 500, and then I put 10%
into very speculative public market
investing, and then I put 10% into
uh like
you know, private opportunities, right?
And
the private opportunities, I'm net zero,
but I think there's one winner in the
portfolio that'll pay for everything.
And that's the only way you get that
money in 50 years.
>> VC investment. Standard angel investing.
Yeah. Yeah, yeah. And I've I've deployed
hundreds of thousands of dollars into
just random ideas people have emailed
me, and a lot of them are the big fat
zeros. But I think I got I think I got
one big winner in there. I've It's funny
like I have I use Monarch for my
finances, and I have a section that has
all of my like angel private
investments, and I don't even include
any of those in my net worth totals
because I'm like, "I need to just assume
they're all zeros." But it's like a it's
the same deal, Shawn. It's like I have
two or three that are like going to make
the whole portfolio. But it's also like
I don't know, when do those pay out? 5
years, 10 years, 15 years? Who knows?
Like on paper they're going to be a
really good return percentage, but I
don't know when. And And this is a like
Basically, you shouldn't do anything in
angel investing until you don't need
money at all. Like that's the irony.
Like when you hear about, "Oh, he was an
angel investor in Uber." Well, if
if he was an angel investor, then he
probably didn't need money any anymore
by the time he made that investment
anyway. Because when you put money in as
an angel, like
first of all, the chances of that
company being worth anything are very
low, and then like the We We already
talked about like the path to free cash
flow is usually 5, 6 years even for a
successful company. What's the path
toward to an acquisition or an IPO? 10,
15? I mean, it's it's a while. Yeah,
look, yeah. And who knows what the
future looks like.
Okay, I got to take a break and tell you
a quick story from a few weeks ago.
We were at E-commerce Fuel Live. This is
Andrew's live event that he does once a
year. It's like 200 brands. They do a
great job. And this story is just too
good not to share, so I bear with me
while I tell it.
And I'm at the opening night party. I'm
talking with Amit, CEO of Richpanel, one
of the great sponsors of this podcast.
And Amit and I are having a good chat,
and beside me walks in Katie to say hi
to Amit. You know, Amit looks up, and I
swear to God this is true. He goes,
"Hey, Matt, is this your EA?"
And before I could react, Katie
absolutely dares him a new one and says,
"I am not Matt's EA. Matt is my EA." So,
if you ever wanted a lesson in how to
stick your foot firmly in your own
mouth, this is it. Amit could not catch
a break the rest of this event,
deservedly so, right? And by the end of
it, I think she actually said, "I will
never switch to Richpanel unless you
give me a 100% discount." Now, I know
this is a strange sponsor read, but I I
just needed to tell the story cuz I
think it's kind of funny. So, I don't
think Katie's going to get a 100%
discount, but honestly, I don't think
you need it. Switching to Richpanel is
going to pay for itself anyway. They are
genuinely one of the best teams to work
with. I mean that. We work with them at
our brands. They have more than paid for
themselves and their software. So, if
you want to reduce tickets by like 30%
or more, save on your SaaS bill, go into
Black Friday without any chaos,
give Richpanel a shot. Just go to
richpanel.com/demo.
And Amit, if you're listening, dude,
that's just a terrible
terrible example of what you say to
somebody when you meet them the first
time. Oh, and Amit promised me there's
actually a super special promo code.
If you use sorrykatie,
sorry k a t y, you'll get 20% off your
subscription. Give it a shot.
I do want to circle back, and I want to
start defining some stuff for people.
So,
uh Jason brought up the rule of 40,
okay? And that is he explained it. 40%
income
you so you know, EBITDA or 40% growth or
some combination of those to whatever
you get to. But I want to to talk about
the the P&L balance statement. How can
you get that at e-commerce? Because I
don't think any e-commerce brands have
40% EBITDA margins. It's just too high
for us to get, right? And that's because
And you shouldn't. I mean, I think
that's part of the point Jason would
make is like if you are at 40% EBITDA
margins, it's because you're under
investing somewhere in your business.
You're You're doing something wrong.
You just have to determine what are your
what are you know, what your goals are,
right? Building enterprise value, you
know, you're
you need
You need top line growth. Valuation is
driven by the top line growth rate and
EBITDA margin. I mean, that's what
drives the valuation at the end of the
day of an invest investors.
Um so, those are the like the decisions
that you make are are basically based on
that, right? Um what am I How am I going
to drive enterprise value? It's It's a
combination of top line growth and and
margin.
We hit 27%
one year, and and it was like looking
back, I'm like, we under invested in
areas of the business. I didn't feel
that way necessarily at the time, but it
was like 27% obviously like a baller
EBITDA margin, and the EBITDA was
awesome, but it was also like I think we
felt it some the next year cuz we we
should have been reinvesting in some
ways.
Yeah, so like okay, you have $100
million in net revenue. What does net
revenue mean? It means after discount,
returns, everything that goes above
that. So What they pay you. What people
send you, you know, from that those
sales, right? Yeah, so so maybe it's 120
million gross sales, but it's 100
million net, okay? Now, 100 million net,
3 million's coming off the top for
payment processing rates. That's just
the reality of it. So, you have 97
million dollars left. You have to pay
for the cost of your goods, which if
you're amazing, is 10 or 15%, right?
Now, maybe it's 20%. Let's call 20%.
We're down to 77. You have to pay for
the freight to come into America, and
then into your customer's hands. If
you're a lucky, that's 10%, okay? Now,
we're at 67%. So, the That's called your
gross margin. Your gross margin now is
67% minus selling fees and everything
else. You got to pay Amazon. Well, let's
say it's covered in that 3%, whatever.
I'm just going to say you're at 65%
gross margin. Now, you have to spend
money on marketing, okay? If you're If
you're my brand, almost half your
revenue's going to marketing. If you're
Mike's brand, it's 5 or 10% going to
marketing, right? Let's just call it But
it has to be because our gross margins
are so much smaller than yours. And And
so like this is you got to play the hand
that's dealt you. Like there's times
when I'm like, "Man, I wish I could
spend 50% of revenue on marketing. We
would have a lot more brand recognition,
but I just can't cuz I'm hemmed in by
gross margins."
Yeah, and the point of this exercise is
to show everybody that like at the end
of the day, all the brands are the same.
It's [laughter] like there's only so
many of these buckets. The only thing
that changes is the widget, and then the
like the mechanics of the widget. And I
want to make a point here, Shawn. So,
there's a great article I've referenced
it here before that Bill Gurley talked
about
the LTV, and he uses an analogy that I
really like. And that is that a lot of
the key variables or and think about it
this way, a lot of the parts of your
P&L, they pull on each other. So, for
example, the higher your gross margin,
the higher your marketing budget as a
percentage of revenue will have to be.
Because the higher your prices, the more
you're going to have to convince people
to buy the thing. The more attractive
you're going to have to make it look.
The more you're going to have to pay
influencers to push it. Um so, for Or
you can go, "Hey, the more attractive
your price point, the smaller percentage
you have to spend on marketing." And
that actually there's several areas of
your business that work that way where
they tug on each other. It's not just
like, "Oh, I can keep my marketing
percentage the same. I can raise prices,
and then boom, all that's going to fall
to the bottom line." It's like, "No,
doesn't work that way." Because those
things tug in different directions, and
they pull each other. So, like Shawn's
saying, you end up getting to the same
place, but sometimes in like really
radically different ways. We had this
We We have internal projections we build
like with our profit model and our our
income statement.
And uh my guy who who runs it, Brett, he
built one in early April. And then we
just basically like threw that file away
cuz it was like there's a trade war,
everything has changed, every assumption
in there is wrong. They pulled it back
out in the beginning of this month and
they looked at April, May, June, July,
August, I think. They looked at a
5-month period and we were within 15,000
of the EBITDA projected in his model.
But you know what? We got to it in a
really really different way than we
thought we were going to because like
the world really changed, but we somehow
ended up producing the same amount of
EBITDA that we thought we were going to
produce. It's just hey, we had way more
marketing and our margins were way lower
and our top line was higher, but our
gross profit Anyway, you you get the
idea. These things pull against each
other and that's why there tend to be
industry standards for EBITDA margins
and stuff like that is that like whether
you go heavy marketing or heavy margins
or whatever, you end up at the same
place.
Yeah, look. Everyone's given a box of
100 Legos, build whatever you want, but
you can't add any more Legos, right? And
and and and that's what this business
is. So in in my fake business, I had 65%
gross margins. I got to spend 25% on
marketing. I'm down to 40%. I haven't
paid contractors, I haven't paid for
insurance, and I haven't paid my people.
>> Your people. Yeah. Yeah. So it's like
very quickly that gets to 25% EBITDA.
That's like a pretty That was just
randomly made up. That'd be amazing. For
everybody listening, if you're at 25%
EBITDA, congratulations. You're you're
winning probably in in business. But
more more likely, Sean, you said 25% on
marketing. Somebody running 65% gross
margins is probably running more like
35, 45, 50%.
Yeah.
>> Yeah, yeah. I I think like 35 would be
would be very uh reasonable. And that's
the thing about that every publicly
traded company reports on a gross margin
number and Yeti's like 50% or 45% or
whatever, right? Nike's at 45%.
>> You're saying 45% of revenue on
marketing?
No, no. So I'm talking I'm talking gross
margin.
>> Yeah, gross margin. Got it. After
selling their products, they only have
$45 out of every $100 they get back. And
then they have to pay for marketing and
everything else. So 65 percent or $65
gross margin on a $100 cost of goods is
near best in class, right? You have to
be really really special to get that
done. Your name needs to be Jason Panzer
and you got to be selling something
special. Well, and this is like one of
the more shocking moments for me was
when I realized our EBITDA margins were
better than Yeti's cuz I'm like that
that can't be right. Like how would that
be true? But another thing that I
realized is like nominal dollars are
what pay paychecks. And so this is the
other thing about getting too obsessed
with percentages is that so if I sell a
bunch of water bottles at $25 and I have
you know, 20% EBITDA margins, let's say.
But Yeti sells a bunch of $50 water
bottles and they have 15% EBITDA
margins, they're going to make a heck of
a lot more money than I am because their
their ring per bottle is way higher and
they're getting that percentage on a
much bigger nominal number. So it it
this is where you have to like kind of
marry those two ideas together to get
the best financial outcomes is like
yeah, I've got percentage goals, but
also like I have to think about things
like what is my nominal average selling
price and things like that. Also, the
cost to be public is about $10 million a
year. So uh Allbirds is public on
whatever, $200 million a year in revenue
and they're spending $10 million a year
to be public. So
>> so bad for the Allbirds. I I just it it
just feels like it's it's too easy. It's
too easy for that to be like the
example, you know? Yeah. Well, they they
should go private. Okay, the last thing
I wanted to summarize was
um Mike brought up working cash, maybe
it was Jason, working cash versus
investable cash versus free cash. So
like just everyone should think about
this.
Your business all is a steady state
needs some money to operate. You have to
pay payroll before money comes in, you
have to pay whatever. That's working
capital in your business. And if you
want to get crazy, you set inventory to
that it's like hey look, you always need
$30 is tied up in your business in some
way or the other, either cash in the
bank account or sitting there as a pile
of wallets in your warehouse, right?
That doesn't really change. It it can
never really go down Unless your
business shrinks. Yeah, yeah, exactly,
right?
>> Which is one of the counterintuitive
things like we shrunk top line this
year.
And so you would think wow, cash is not
going to be great. Our cash is
exploding.
Right? Because you don't need as much
working capital. Like when you're not
growing, you don't need as much working
capital and that was like really
counterintuitive for me. When you're
growing, it's the opposite. Like your
working capital's having to grow and so
you're having to insert cash into the
business.
So again, it's just counterintuitive how
cash can flow in and out. Mike, you said
one offhand comment that um you like
maybe you'll have too much free cash,
you don't know what to do with it. It's
like that's when companies explore M&A.
That's when that's when you should go
buy, you know, a kid shoe company or
whatever. It's because if you have too
much money and you don't know what to do
with it in your business, you either do
dividends for the next, you know, three
or four years or you try to grow the
business through artificially through
M&A.
So if you want to buy a wallet company,
I know one, man.
Uh is it is it affordable?
>> [laughter]
>> Dude, for you, you're going to get a
sweetheart deal.
>> know I want a power bank company. Do you
know anyone, Sean? Working on it, man.
Um all right. I think there's a great
pod in there, but I want to thank all
the listeners. You are what makes
Operators function as an organization.
We have full-time employees, we have
Aaron, we have everybody. We have
wonderful sponsors in Fulfill, North
Beam, Post Script, Saracen Analytics,
and Rich Panel. Five softwares all of us
are paying and using for. Jason, you're
paying for every software on earth. We
appreciate that, man. You're keeping the
lights on in this business.
>> [laughter]
>> Uh we have a newsletter you got to
subscribe to. We have new shows coming
out all the time, Operators Titans, a
special exclusive 10-episode series with
the best of the best sponsored by Apple
loving. We love them. I spend money
there as an ad channel. I also want to
thank eCom Fuel. We got eCom Fuel.
They're going to start playing the music
and take me off stage now.
>> buddy. And what are all the things you
can thank? Dude, look, I'm I'm having a
great year. We didn't talk about how um
Liberation Day totally up so many
businesses. That'll be the next episode,
so stay tuned for that. But uh look,
we've had a friend die of a brain tumor
this year. We had houses burn down for
our co-founders.
I mean, I there's a laundry list of
horrible things that have happened this
year. Um with that being said,
I'm super happy, I'm super healthy. The
year's ending strong. We got plenty of
cash. Everything's going fine. So even
in the hardest years ever,
it's all worth doing. So thank you for
being here.
>> By the way, I just got to say this. I
love when Sean does optimistic Sean
tweets because like my Twitter feed is
just like rife with negativity and I
almost don't even want to go to Twitter
anymore as much as I love I you know, I
grew up literally like I've been on
Twitter since it started. But there's so
much negativity and I just I just love
the Sean positive tweets. So keep them
coming, buddy.
>> The return Sean, the the tone on your
return to Twitter has been
chef's kiss. And I I just think that
it's like it's a choice. Life's a
choice, the perspective you choose to
take. On this show, we're always going
to take the positive perspective and the
optimistic perspective and maybe that's
because we're insane, you know, as
e-commerce operators, but like I'm I
love it. I love that we get to build
businesses and even though it's been a
crazy year, like what a freaking
opportunity. What an amazing like world
that we live in like with the way that
we can build companies today.
So I I love it when you you take that
tone and I want that to be the tone of
the show also. Like you shared in chat
the a screenshot of some of the feedback
that we've gotten from someone who like
this has really helped them to
accomplish things that wouldn't have
been possible, they said, without the
show. And man, that's the content I'm
here for. I I love that.
Oh dude, and look, I I am I am readily
available. If you're an eCom operator
and you're having a hard time, reach out
to me. I I will help you however I can.
I get on free consulting calls all the
time. I don't need any money, so I'm
here to help everybody. But if you're a
SaaS person trying to sell me, please
don't email me. This is just for
e-commerce operators. I want to try to
help them. If you need funding,
>> Email Jason. If you're a SaaS provider,
[laughter]
That's so true. Jason does lead gen. So
it's just I'll be his email.
>> out a dividend recap to do more
softwares. That's what I heard. They
[laughter] just want to funnel all that
money into software.
Dude, uh no, positivity nonstop, guys.
We're we're killing it. The future's so
beautiful. We have a note from our
producer in chat. What what what are
they saying? Email Aaron. eCom, yep.
[laughter]
Yep. So if you want to be in touch with
uh with Operators and you're a SaaS
vendor, Aaron, he's available. Just talk
to him. Goodbye, everybody. Thanks for
being here. Later, boys.
>> [music]